this is a librivox recording all librivox recordings are in the public
domain for more information or to volunteer please visit librivox.org this recording by jay hall
the Wonderful Wizard of Oz by l frank Baum Chapter 12 The Search for the
Wicked Witch The soldier with the green whiskers led them through the streets of
the Emerald City until they reach the room where the Guardian of the Gates
lived. This officer unlocked their spectacles to put them back in his great
box, and then he politely opened the gate for our friends. “Which road leads to the
Wicked Witch of the West?” asked Dorothy.
“There is no road,” answered the Guardian of the Gates.
“No one ever wishes to go that way.” “How, then, are we to find her?” inquired the
girl. “That will be easy,” replied the man, “for when she knows you are in the
country of the Winkies she will find you, and make you all her slaves.”
“Perhaps not,” said the Scarecrow, “for we mean to destroy her.” “Oh, that is different,”
said the Guardian of the Gates. “No one has ever destroyed her before, so
naturally I thought she would make slaves of you, as she has dubbed the rest.
But take care; for she is wicked and fierce, and may not allow you to destroy
her. Keep to the West, where the sun sets, and you cannot fail to find her.” They
thanked him and bade him goodbye and turned toward the West, walking over
fields of soft grass dotted here and there with daisies and buttercups.
Dorothy still wore the pretty silk dress she had put on in the palace, but now, to
her surprise, she found it was no longer green, but pure white ribbon around
Toto’s neck had also lost its green color and was as white as Dorothy’s
dress. The Emerald City was soon left far behind. As they advanced the ground
became rougher and hillier, for there was no farms nor houses in this country of
the West, and the ground was untilled. In the afternoon the sun shone hot in their
faces, for there were no trees to offer them shade; so that before night Dorothy
and Toto and the Lion were tire and lay down upon the grass and fell
asleep, with the Woodman and the Scarecrow keeping watch. Now the Wicked
Witch of the West had but one eye, yet that was as powerful as a telescope, and
she could see everywhere. So, as she sat in the door of her castle, she happened
to look around and saw Dorothy lying asleep, with her friends all about They
were a long distance off, but the Wicked Witch was angry to find them in her country;
so she blew upon a silver whistle that hung around her neck. At once there came
running to her from all directions a pack of great wolves. They had long legs
and fierce eyes and sharp teeth. “Go to those people,” said the Witch, “and tear
them to pieces.” “Are you not going to make them your slaves?” asked the leader of the
wolves. “No,” she answered, “one is of tin, and
one of straw; one is a girl and another a
new Lion. None of them is fit to work, so you may tear them into small pieces.”
“Very well,” said the wolf, and he dashed away at full speed, followed by the
others. It was lucky the Scarecrow and the Woodman were wide awake and heard
the wolves coming. “This is my fight,” said the woman so get behind me and I
will meet them as they come.” He seized his axe, which he had made very sharp, and
as the leader of the wolves came on the Tin Woodman swung his arm and chopped
the wolf’s head from its body, so that it immediately died. As soon as he could
raise his axe another wolf came up, and he also fell under the sharp edge of the
Tin Woodman’s weapon. There were forty wolves, and forty times a wolf was killed,
so that at last they all lay dead in a heap before the Woodman he put down his
axe and sat beside the Scarecrow, who said, “It was a good fight, friend.” They
waited until jour thea woke the next morning. The little girl was quite
frightened when she saw the great pile of shaggy wolves, but the Tin Woodman
told her all. She thanked him for saving them and sat down to breakfast, after
which they started again upon their journey. Now the same morning the Wicked
Witch came to the door of her castle and out with her one eye that could see far
off. She saw all her wolves lying dead, and the strangers still traveling
through her country. This made her angrier than before, and she blew her
silver whistle twice straight away a great flock of wild crows came flying
toward her, enough to darken the sky. And the Wicked Witch said to the King Crow,
“Fly at once to the strangers pick out their eyes and tear them to pieces.” The
wild crows flew in one great flock toward Dorothy and her companions. When
the little girl saw them coming she was afraid. But the Scarecrow said, “This is my
battle, so lie down beside me and you will not be harmed.” So they all lay upon
the ground except the Scarecrow, and he stood up and stretched out his arms. And
when the crow saw him they were frightened, as these birds always are by
scarecrows, and did not dare to come any nearer. But the King Crow said: “It is only
a stuffed man. I will peck his eyes out.” The King Crow flew at the Scarecrow, who
caught it by the head and twisted its neck until it died. And then another crow
flew at him, and the Scarecrow twisted its neck also. There were forty crows, and
forty times the Scarecrow twisted a neck, until at last all were lying dead beside
him. Then he called to his companions to rise, and again they went upon their
journey. When the Wicked Witch looked out again and saw all her crows lying in a
heap, she got into a terrible rage, and blew three times upon her silver whistle.
Forthwith there was heard a great buzzing in the air, and a swarm of black
bees came flying toward her. “Go to the strangers and sting them to death!”
commanded the Witch, and the bees turned and flew rapidly until they came to
where Dorothy and her friends were walking. But the Woodman had seen them
coming, and this ere crow had decided what to do. “Take out my straw and scatter
it over the little girl and the dog and the Lion,” he said to the Woodman, “and the
bees cannot sting them.” This the Woodman did, and his Dorothy lay close beside the
Lion and held Toto in her arms, the straw covered them entirely. The bees came and
found no one but the Woodman distinct so they flew at him and broke off all their
stings against the ten without hurting the Woodman at all. And as bees cannot
live when their stings are broken that was the end of the black bees, and they
lay scattered thick about the Woodman, like little heaps of fine coal. Then
Dorothy and the Lion got up, and the girl helped the Tin Woodman put the straw
back into the Scarecrow again, until he was as good as ever.
So they started upon their journey once more. The Wicked Witch was so angry when
she saw her black bees and little heaps like fine coal that she stamped her foot
and tore her hair and gnashed her teeth.
And then she called a dozen of her slaves, who were the Winkies, and gave
them sharp spears, telling them to go to the strangers and destroy them. The
Winkies were not a brave people, but they had to do as they were told.
So they marched away until they came near to Dorothy.
Then the Lion gave a great roar and sprang towards them, and the poor Winkies
were so frightened that they ran back as fast as they could. When they returned to
the castle the Wicked Witch beat them well with a strap, and sent them back to
their work, after which she sat down to think what she would do next. She could
not understand how all her plans to destroy these strangers had failed; but
she was a powerful Witch, as well as a wicked one, and she soon made up her mind
how to act. There was, in her cupboard, a Golden Cap, with a circle of diamonds and
rubies running round it. This Golden Cap had a charm. Whoever owned it could call
three times upon the Winged Monkeys, who would obey any order they were given. But
no person could command these strange creatures more than three times. Twice
already the Wicked Witch had used the charm of the Cap. Once was when she had
made the Winkies her slaves, and set herself to rule over their country. The
Winged Monkeys had helped her do this.
The second time was when she had fought against the Great Oz himself, and had
driven him out of the land of the West.
The Winged Monkeys had also helped her in doing this. Only once more could she use this gold
Cap, for which reason she did not like to do so until all her other powers were
exhausted. But now that her fierce wolves and her wild crows and her stinging bees
were gone, and her slaves had been scared away by the Cowardly Lion, she saw that
there was only one way left to destroy Dorothy and her friends. So the Wicked
Witch took the Golden Cap from her cupboard and placed it upon her head.
Then she stood upon her left foot and said, slowly Eppie Pepe kaki then she
stood upon her right foot and said hello hello hello After this she stood upon both feet and
cried in a loud voice dizzy Suzie zyk Now the charm began to work. The sky was
darkened, and a low rumbling sound was heard in the air. There was a rushing of
many wings, a great chattering and laughing, and the sun came out of the
dark sky to show the Wicked Witch surrounded by a crowd of monkeys, each
with a pair of immense and powerful wings on its shoulders. One, much bigger
than the others, seemed to be their leader.
He flew close to the Witch and said, “You have called us for the third and last
time. What do you command?” “Go to the strangers who are within my land to
destroy them all except the Lion,” said the Wicked Witch. “Bring that beast to me,
for I have a mind to harness him like a horse, and make him work.” “Your command
shall be obeyed,” said the leader. Then, with a great deal of chattering and noise, the Winged
Monkeys flew away to the place where Dorothy and her friends were walking.
Some of the monkey sees the Tin Woodman and carried him through the air until
they were over a country thickly covered with sharp rocks. Here they dropped the
poor Woodman, who fell a great distance to the rocks, where he lay so battered
and dented that he could neither move nor groan. Others of the Monkeys caught
the Scarecrow, and with their long fingers pulled all of the straw out of his clothes and head.
They made his hat and boots and clothes into a small bundle and threw it
the top branches of a tall tree. The remaining Monkeys threw pieces of stout
rope around the Lion and while Minnie coils around his body and head and legs,
until he was unable to bite or scratch or struggle in any way. Then they lifted
him up and flew away with him to the Witch’s castle, where he was placed in a
small yard with a high iron fence around it, so that he could not escape. But
Dorothy they did not harm at all. She stood, with Toto in her arms,
watching the sad fate of her comrades and thinking it would soon be her turn.
The leader of the Winged Monkeys flew up to her, his long, hairy arms stretched out
and his ugly face grinning terribly; but he saw the mark of the Good Witch’s kiss
upon her forehead and stopped short, motioning to the others not to touch her.
“We dare not harm this little girl,” he said to them, “for she is protected by the
Power of Good, and that is greater than the Power of Evil. All we can do is to
carry her to the castle of the Wicked Witch and leave her there.”
So, carefully and gently, they lifted Dorothy in their arms and carried her
swiftly through the air until they came to the castle, where they set her down
upon the front doorstep. Then the leader said to the which We have obeyed you as
far as we were able. The Tin Woodman and the Scarecrow are destroyed, and the Lion
is tied up in your yard. The little girl we dare not harm, nor the dog she carries
in her arms. Your power over our band is now ended, and you will never see us
again.” Then all the Winged Monkeys, with much laughing and chattering and noise,
flew into the air and were soon out of sight. The Wicked Witch was both
surprised and worried when she saw the mark on Dorothy’s forehead, for she knew
well that neither the Winged Monkeys nor she, herself, dare hurt the girl in any
way. She looked down at Dorothy’s feet, and seeing the Silver Shoes, began to
tremble with fear, for she knew that a powerful charm belonged to them. At first
the Witch was tempted to run away from Dorothy; but she happened to look into
the child’s eyes and saw how simple the soul behind them was, and that the little
girl did not know of the wonderful power the Silver Shoes gave her.
So the Wicked Witch laughed to herself, and thought, “I can still make her my
slave, for she does not know how to use her power.” Then she said to Dorothy,
harshly and severely: “Come with me; and see that you mind everything I tell you
or if you do not I will make an end of
you, as I did of the ten Woodman and the Scarecrow.” Dorothy followed her through
many of the beautiful rooms in her castle until they came to the kitchens
where the Witch bade her clean the pots and kettles and sweep the floor and keep
the fire fed with wood. Dorothy went to work meekly, with her mind made up to
work as hard as she could; for she was glad the Wicked Witch had decided not to
kill her. With Dorothy hard at work, the Witch thought she would go into the
courtyard and harness the Cowardly Lion like a horse; it would amuse her, she was
sure, to make him draw her chariot whenever she wished to go to drive. But
as she opened the gate the Lion gave a loud roar and bounded at her so fiercely
that the Witch was afraid, and ran out and shut the gate again. “If I cannot
harness you,” said the Witch to the Lion, speaking through the bars of the gate, “I
can starve you. You shall have nothing to eat until you do as I wish.” So after that
she took no food to the imprisoned Lion; but every day she came to the gate at
noon and asked, “Are you ready to be harnessed like a horse?” And the Lion
would answer, “No you come in this yard, I will bite you.” The reason the Lion did
not have to do is the Witch wished was that every night, while the woman was
asleep, Dorothy carried him food from the cupboard. After he had eaten he would lie
down on his bed of straw, and Dorothy would lie down beside him and put her
head in his soft, shaggy mane, while they talked of their troubles and tried to
plan some way to escape. But they could find no way to get out of the castle, for
it was constantly guarded by the yellow Winkies, who were the slaves of the
Wicked Witch and were too afraid of her not to do as she told them. The girl had
to work hard during the day, and often the Witch threatened to beat her with
the same old umbrella she always carried in her hand.
But, in truth, she did not dare to strike Dorothy, because of the mark upon her
forehead. The child did not know this, and was full of fear for herself in Toto.
Once the which struck Toto a blow with her umbrella and the brave little dog
flew at her and bit her leg in return.
The Witch did not bleed where she was bitten, for she was so wicked that the
blood in her had dried up many years before. Dorothy’s life became very sad as
she grew to understand that it would be harder than ever to get back to Kansas
and Aunt Em again.
Sometimes she would cry bitterly for hours, with Toto sitting at her feet and
looking into her face, whining Disney to show how sorry he was
for his little mistress. Toto did not really care whether he was in Kansas or
the Land of Oz so long as Dorothy was with him; but he knew the little girl was
unhappy, and that made him unhappy too.
Now the Wicked Witch had a great longing to have for her own the Silver Shoes
which the girl always wore. Her bees and her crows and her wolves were lying in
heaps and drying up, and she had used up all the power of the Golden Cap; but if
she could only get ahold of the Silver Shoes, they would give her more power
than all the other things she had lost.
She watched Dorothy carefully, to see if she ever took off her shoes, thinking she
might steal them. But the child was so proud of her pretty shoes that she never
took them off except at night when she took her bath. The Witch was too much
afraid of the dark to dare go into Dorothy’s room at night to take the
shoes, and her dread of water was greater than her fear of the dark, so she never
came near when Dorothy was bathing.
Indeed, the old Witch never touched water, nor ever let water touch her in any way.
But the wicked creature was very cunning, and she finally thought of a trick that
would give her what she wanted. She placed a bar of iron in the middle of
the kitchen floor, and then by her magic arts made the iron invisible to human
eyes. So that when Dorothy walked across the floor she stumbled over the bar, not
being able to see it, and fell at full length. She was
not much hurt, but in her fall one of the Silver Shoes came off; and before she
could reach it, the Witch had snatched it away and put it on her own
skinny foot. The wicked woman was greatly pleased with the success of her trick,
for as long as she had one of the shoes she owned half the power of their charm,
and Dorothy could not use it against her, even had she known how to do so. The
little girl, seeing she had lost one of her pretty shoes, grew angry, and said to the Witch,
“Give me back my shoe!” “I will not,” retorted
the Witch, “for it is now my shoe, and not yours.” “You are a wicked creature!” cried
Dorothy. “You have no right to take my shoe from me.” “I shall keep it, just the
same,” said the Witch, laughing at her, “and someday I shall get the other one from you, too.”
This made Dorothy so very angry that she picked up the bucket of water that stood
near and dashed it over the Witch, wetting her from head to foot. Instantly
the wicked woman gave a loud cry of fear, and then, as Dorothy looked at her in
wonder, the Witch began to shrink and fall away. “See what you have done!” she
screamed. “In a minute I shall melt away.” “I’m very sorry, indeed,” said Dorothy, who
was truly frightened to see the Witch actually melting away like brown sugar
before her very eyes. “Didn’t you know water would be the end of me?” asked the
Witch, in a wailing, despairing voice. “Of course not,” answered Dorothy.
“How should I?” “Well, in a few minutes I shall be all melted, and you will have
the castle to yourself. I have been wicked in my day, but I have never
thought a little girl like you would ever be able to melt me and in my wicked
deeds. Look out— —here I go!” With these words the Witch fell down in a brown,
melted, shapeless mass and began to spread over the clean boards of the
kitchen floor. Seeing that she had really melted away into nothing, Dorothy drew
another bucket of water and threw it over the mess. She then swept it all out
the door. After picking out the silver shoe, which was all it was left of the
old woman, she cleaned and dried it with a cloth,
and put it on her foot again. Then, being
at last free to do as she chose, she ran out to the courtyard to tell the Lion
that the Wicked Witch of the West had come to an end, and that they were no
longer prisoners in a strange land